Survival Technique

by POUL ANDERSON AND KENNETH 'GRAY

A different historical period of this earth may be even more alien to Twentieth-Century Man than the most remote planet, as Poul Anderson has pointed out before, notably in The Man Who Came Early (in the first-published the best from f&sf: sixth series). In this deftly entertaining new tale we see the contrast between our own era and Augustan Rome, and learn why the first prerequisite of successful time travel must be the mastery of Survival Technique.

THE EMPIRE STATE UNIVERSITY

New York 30, N. Y.

College of Science and

Engineering

Department of Physics

May 20,1967

Mr. James K. Maury c/o Adventurers’ Club 430 Hudson Street New York 14, N. Y.

Dear Mr. Maury:

Your name has been given to me by Mr, Roger McIntyre, and I am therefore writing to ask whether you would be interested in joining a most unusual expedition sponsored by this department and the history section of the Arts College under a research grant from UNESCO.

You are doubtless aware from both newspaper and professional accounts that the Homolka reformulation of general relativity theory has been triumphantly confirmed by Goldberg’s experiments in spatiotemporal projection, and that the device loosely known as a “time machine” is not only possible but is actually being completed in our laboratories. Pilot models have already sent human volunteers into distant regions of the earth and recent sections of the past, and brought them back unharmed. For the final test, a three-man expedition to Augustan Rome, 1 a.d., is being planned, and on the basis of Mr. McIntyre’s recommendation we should very much like to include you.

Without going into the theory of the projector, I shall briefly discuss the practical aspect. Our three explorers will be sent from the laboratory of this year to first-century Rome. They will, of course, have been previously instructed in the Latin language and customs, and will be given appropriate garb and sufficient, proper money for a three-week stay. During that time they will not reveal their identity, except in the improbable event of extreme emergency—not that the past can be “upset,” but it would complicate their mission, which will be simply to mingle with the people and take notes on those small questions of detail (mores, attitudes, etc.) which are not discussed in surviving contemporary chronicles. At the end of the period, they will return to the exact spot of their materialization, and the projector field will again be generated to return them to this point of space-time.

Actually, they will return three weeks later than they left, because of the balance effect. In simple terms, the laws of conservation require that when a given mass is displaced into the past, the same mass must be brought up to the present; in fact, it must be both physically and chemically similar, within narrow limits of tolerance. In short, when we send our three men to ancient Rome, the field will automatically select three Romans of roughly equal size from the vicinity and carry them to our laboratory. By questioning these Romans during their stay with us, our historians expect to gain much other valuable information. At the end of the arbitrary three-week period, they will be returned as our men come back to the present.

Needless to say, our personnel must be carefully chosen. Though furnished with automatic pistols, and any other inconspicuous equipment that may be indicated, they should use them only as a last resort. Quite apart from humanitarian considerations, such use would vitiate the scientific purpose of the expedition, since it would make them conspicuous figures, regarded with awe and therefore cut off from the daily life which they have been sent to observe. We need men not only of courage, resource, and training, but of tact and quick wits.

Already we have coopted Mr. McIntyre, as you know a skilled anthropologist, and Dr. Simon Harbold, who is a noted Classical historian. In addition we need a man who is an athlete with experience of alien cultures. Your record as soldier and explorer makes you eminently qualified.

Accordingly, I am happy to offer it to you. If you are interested, I will supply any further details you wish, and salary can be discussed. I trust to hear from you at your earliest convenience.

Very sincerely yours,

J. Worthington Barr Chairman of the Department

J. WORTHINGTON BARR = DEPT. OF PHYSICS EMPIRE STATE UNIVERSITY = NEW YORK NY — YOU BET MAURY —

Official transcript from tape recording

July 14,196 7

Dr. Barr: At this great moment, gentlemen, at this great moment in the advance of mankind from savagery to undreamed of heights, I think it wisest not only to film this great event as it happens, as it occurs, but to keep a running commentary. Although representatives of the press are among us, the sacred obligation of science is to have a record as given by trained observers. Underline that: trained observers. . . . Ah . . . Present are myself, J. Worthington Barr, Chairman of the Department of Physics; President Johnson of this great university; Dean Clausewitz of the College of Arts; Dr. Langdon, professor of Latin; and, of course, the various technicians and scientists, as well as representatives of—Ah! Mr. Maury! Here come Mr, Maury, Mr. McIntyre, and Dr. Harbold, our three intrepid emissaries to ancient Rome. Come over here, please, gentlemen. The projector is quite ready to go. Have you any statements you wish to make?

Maury: Yes. How the devil do I keep this toga on straight?

Dr. Barr: Hah-hah, you will have your little joke.

McIntyre: One thing worries me. I feel adept enough at Latin—I ought to, after that course they put us through!—but how, uh, I mean are we sure our costumes are authentic?

Harbold: I thought you knew, Roger. They probably aren’t. We can’t be sure of all these little details. That’s what this expedition is for, to find out such things.

McIntyre: OK, OK. But if we’re not supposed to admit we’re time travelers—

Maury: Just a precaution, Mac. They wouldn’t believe us, that’s all, and we don’t want to be locked in the nut house when the time comes for us to go back.

Harbold: Don’t worry too much about the clothes. Our accent is doubtless wrong too. But we’re not going to claim to be Romans. We’ll be foreigners, Germans with a smattering of education, like Arminius you know. Rome was full of outlanders.

Maury: And if we should run into real trouble—well, I’ve been in trouble before now. One time in the Sinkiang Desert—

McIntyre: You have the guns. I’ll leave the shooting to you.

Maury: There shouldn’t have to be any. Actually, with all our technical knowledge, we could support ourselves very nicely. Introduce pinball games and steam engines and whatnot. Or Harbold here could set up as a prophet—he’ll know what's going to happen next.

Dean Clausewitz :That will not be necessary. You have ample funds.

Maury: I know, I know. Well just investigate the customs . . . and I understand those Roman customs were very interesting!

Dr. Barr: Ahem! Naturally, the reputation of this institution-decorum—

Maury: Don't be afraid, doc. It won’t all get in the official report.

Dr. Barr: I believe the press representatives would like to see you. You have ten minutes till, ah, zero hour.

Maury: Sure. And don’t worry about us. We’ve got two thousand years of progress behind us. If you must worry about something, worry about Rome! . . .

Dr. Barr; There they, ah, go. Good-by, gentlemen! Good luck!

Dean Clausewitz: Stand by, here come the Romans!

President Johnson: Good heavens . . . there, under the lens . . . three of them! Are the guards ready ?

Dr. Langdon: Yes. But I don’t expect these people will get violent. Look at them huddling—the poor creatures must be half mad with fright. They’re going to have to be protected from the psychic shock of transportation into a culture as far ahead of theirs as ours is.

Dr. Barr: Why—why, one of them is a young woman!

President Johnson: Er, not unattractive, is she? But so, um, poverty-stricken.

Dr. Barr: They all are. Look at those dirty tunics—in rags! And the two men haven’t shaved for a week, I’ll be bound. Look at the big one—what a brute I

Dean Clausewitz: It was to be expected on the basis of probability, you know. More paupers than aristocrats in any century. And, of course, to make them less conspicuous, our men were sent into what we believe was a slum area.

Dr. Barr: True. The machine, ah, selected the three nearest humans to balance . . . They’re standing up! That man there, the small one, he’s walking off the platform toward us!

Dr. Langdon: I’d better go reassure them.

Dr. Barr: A great moment. Where’s that microphone? A great moment in the onward march of science.

Dean Clausewitz: I wonder how our men are making out ... or did make out . . . really, time travel ought to have a separate verb form.

Dr. Barr: No reason to worry about them, Dean Clausewitz. Not only are they men of courage and resource, but they, ah, know the score . . . know what to expect ... a great advantage. Believe me, I anticipated all the contingencies, I am not lacking in imagination.

Dean Clausewitz: What’s the mater with old Langdon? He’s jabbering at them and they’re jabbering back and nobody seems to understand.

Dr. Barr: Could these be, ah, non-Romans too? Visiting foreigners that were by unlucky chance selected—

Dean Clausewitz: Surely not. They look right, you know, just about like modern Italians. . . . Hmmm, they appear to be recovering their self-possession. Look, the young woman’s smiling. I’ll bet if you washed her face and gave her some makeup she’d be quite stunning.

Dr. Langdon : Gentlemen!

Dr. Barr: What is it? What’s the matter?

Dr. Langdon: They don’t understand me, and I don’t understand them. Just a word here and there is all.

Dean Clausewitz: What on earth?

Dr. Langdon: Oh, it’s simple enough. Classical Latin apparently was not pronounced as we have assumed. Our scholars only guessed at it, after all—and to make matters worse, these are slum dwellers. They’re talking some equivalent of Cockney.

Dean Clausewitz: Good Lord! But this ruins the whole experiment! In three weeks we can’t find out—

President Johnson: And what about our poor time travelers?

Dr. Barr: Oh, they will get by, I am sure. But we here seem to be in a quandary.

Mr. Morelli: Excuse me. I think I get that lingo.

Dr. Barr: Oh, Mr. Morelli. This is Mr. Morelli of our physics department. Don’t tell me you understand them?

Mr. Morelli: After a fashion. You see, I speak Italian, and know a little Church Latin to boot. I kind of get the “feel” of it. They want to know what’s happened to them.

Dr. Langton: Excellent! Between us, we ought to—yes, of course, I might have guessed. Italian derives from a Latin corrupted by ignorant folk in the Dark Ages. The Classical pronunciation among the lower classes must have been basically similar. Come on, Morelli, let’s see what we can do.

Dr. Barr: Good. Remove the, ah, subjects to the prepared quarters as soon as possible. Oh, just a moment, here is the photographer from Life. Would you like me to pose with the Romans?—This is a great day for science, a great day!

Memorandum dated July 21,1967

from: Dr. Charles Langdon, Dept, of Classical Languages

to: Dr. K. V. Clausewitz, Dean of the College of Arts

subject: Daily report on spatio-temporal research experiment

We are making rapid progress now that I have the “hang" of their twisted argot. All three are cooperative and express themselves well pleased with the treatment they have received, with an exception noted below.

The man Publius describes himself as an unemployed sailor. He has a large stock of anecdotes about his past adventures; frankly, I doubt his strict veracity, but true or not, his stories furnish a priceless compendium of the details of everyday life. At last the riddle of the trireme has been solved! His words are, of course, being recorded, and a transcript is being prepared. I suggest, however, that access to this transcript be given only to a few properly authorized scholars, since his language and reminiscences may be described as racy. In fact, I do not believe even the original could go through the mails, let alone a translation.

So far Julius has remained evasive about his own life. I gather that he lived by his wits. In brief though colloquial terms, he was a confidence man or racketeer.

The young woman Quintilia has proven extremely cooperative, indeed to a somewhat embarrassing extent. As a fills de joie, she seems to fed called upon to pay for her lodging in the only coin she has. To safeguard the good name of this institution, though without making any insinuations of misconduct to date, I suggest that young Dr, Martens be transferred from this project.

The burden of discussion today dealt with their complaints. Their awe of us has worn off with surprising rapidity. Whether they really understand the idea of spatio- temporal transference is debatable, but at least an accomplished fact no longer impresses them. They unanimously demand to be Jet out of their quarters and offered entertainment, I have given them magazines, but the illustrations only seem to whet their appetites. I suggest that, if possible, some films be shown them, simple slapstick comedy within the grasp of their minds. Furthermore, in view of Quintilia’s profession, I think it would be wisest to lock them into their separate rooms at night.

Tomorrow it is planned that we will take anthropometric measurements.

THE EMPIRE STATE UNIVERSITY

New York 30, N. Y.

Office of the President

July 22,1967

Dr. J .Worthington Barr Department of Physics

Sir:

Since you are in charge of the time project, I must hold you answerable for the catastrophe which has occurred. Kindly let me have the precise circumstances, the names of all concerned, and the steps contemplated to deal with the situation.

Yours truly,

James M. Johnson

President

THE EMPIRE STATE UNIVERSITY

New York 30, N. Y.

College of Science and Engineering

Department of Physics

July 23,1967

Dr. James M. Johnson Office of the President

Dear Sir:

This letter will confirm our conversation of yesterday and serve as my official explanation of the difficulty. I must, however, decline to bear personal responsibility for the incident, nor is my department actually to blame. May I point out that the project was undertaken jointly with the History Dept,?

Briefly, then, as closely as the facts can be ascertained, yesterday at 1:30 p.m. the Roman subjects were called into the common room of their assigned quarters for the scheduled anthropometric studies. Present were Dr. Langdon as interpreter and Drs. Cabot and Simmons of the Department of Anthropology. It was noted that the woman Quintilia had put on modern dress, kindly lent to her by Dr. Langdon’s wife. She had requested such garments three days previously after seeing some pictures in Mademoiselle.

I can only conclude, and my colleagues join with me in this, that the Romans had prepared their scheme in advance and waited until the original precautions of the campus police were relaxed. The report of what happened suffers from a deplorable paucity of precise detail, but the observers agree that Publius volunteered to be measured first. He and Julius removed their clothes. Dr. Langdon requested Quintilia to leave the room meanwhile, but she refused quite profanely. It must be remembered that the Classical world had a different attitude toward nudity from that of our Western Christian Civilization.

Publius sat down in a chair and Drs. Cabot and Simmons bent over him with calipers and notebook. Being a large and powerful man, Publius reached up and, I gather, knocked their heads together. Meanwhile Julius used some variety of judo on Dr. Langdon. Before any of our unhappy colleagues had fully recovered consciousness, they were stripped, bound, and gagged with Dr. Langdon’s garments. Publius and Julius donned the clothes of, respectively, Drs. Cabot and Simmons, and all three subjects thereon left the room,

There are no witnesses to their further actions. They must simply have mingled with the crowd, as this was a period between summer classes, and walked off the campus. Their motives are uncertain, but Dr. Oliver of the Department of Psychology is making an intensive study and has advanced the preliminary hypothesis, subject to correction, that it was a matter of boredom, curiosity and greed.

After all, three slum dwellers might not relish the prospect of being returned to their unfavorable environment. However, on the basis of Gestalt theory, Dr. Hayward disputes this suggestion. Both will submit reports as soon as practicable.

The occurrence is unfortunate, but there is no ground for alarm. I should particularly wish to reassure you in your concern for Maury, McIntyre and Harbold. True, we cannot recover them from the past without projecting three other humans back; but if necessary, the corpses of our three subjects will suffice.

However, such a tragic denouement is hardly probable. I have been in conference with Inspector Brannigan of the Metropolitan Police Force, and he assures me that strangers from another era, totally ignorant of our language and customs, cannot long remain undetected. Indeed, it seems most likely that the fear of such unfamiliar objects as skyscrapers and automobiles will force them to return to us voluntarily. Meanwhile a police dragnet is out, but chiefly for the protection of the Romans themselves, who in their helplessness could possibly meet with some accident.

I await the return, voluntary or enforced, of our subjects at any moment. It is clear from the above, as your own well-known sense of fairness will readily admit, that neither I nor my department can be held in any way responsible; but naturally we offer our fullest cooperation.

Very truly yours,

J. Worthington Barr Chairman of the Department

FEDERAL BUREAU OF INVESTIGATION

Department of Justice

Washington, D. C.

July 30, 1967

Dr. James M. Johnson Office of the President Empire State University New York 30, N. Y.

Dear Sir:

I am in receipt of your telegram of the 30th inst. regarding the disappearance of three Romans of the Augustan Era and the failure of the local police to apprehend them.

Since these people are not American citizens and have not been granted visas, their case would normally fall under the jurisdiction of the Department of Immigration and Naturalization. But since special permission was obtained for your experiment, this bureau is prepared to enter the case. We should, in fact, have been notified immediately, and your delay in doing so will itself have to be investigated.

In the meantime, our New York office will take over the search.

Yours truly,

K. Edward Windhover

Memorandum dated December 18,1967

from: Dr. Alfred Morelli, Dept, of Physics

to: Dr. J. Worthington Barr, Chairman

subject: Development of sweep-field attachment for spatio-temporal projector

This is to let you know that the pilot model of the sweep-field attachment has been tested and proven so satisfactory that a full-scale device can now be constructed. I estimate that we can have it ready in about six weeks, provided we can get the funds. Setting it for the physical characteristics of Maury, McIntyre and Harbold, we can then scan the entire central Mediterranean area of 1 a.d., (or, by then, 2 a.d.) and pick them up wherever they are—or their bodies if they have died.

I’m not so worried about this, though. With their modern background and equipment—well, they can’t change the past, but maybe it’ll turn out that Augustus Caesar had three powerful ministers who really ran the Empire and didn’t get into the history books!

The main stumbling block, aside from the cost, will be getting three humans to exchange for our boys. Since those blasted Romans haven’t turned up yet . . . poor devils, they’re probably in the East River by now. I’d guess they got scared, tried to come back to us, and never made it for some reason. Well, if we don’t find them, we’ll just have to go ahead and use three unclaimed bodies from the morgue. Can you arrange that with the cops? I’m attaching an IBM tabulation of the required physical measurements.

JOURNAL OF THE AMERICAN MEDICAL ASSOCIATION

April 7,1968

Studies of Physical and Psychic

Lesions Incident to the Hazards of Time Travel

by C. Galen, M.D., Ph.D.,

School of Medicine, Empire State University

and E. S. Oliver, Ph.D.,

Department of Psychology, Empire State University

By now the misadventures of the University expedition to Augustan Rome are common knowledge, but it was felt that a scientific study of James K. Maury, Roger McIntyre and Simon Harbold would prove of interest and possibly of value to physicians who may in the future have to treat patients with a similar experience. The following data are published with the permission of the men in question and of the University authorities.

Briefly to recapitulate, they materialized in a slum area at midnight, as planned. The streets of that time being unlighted, and few people abroad, they were not noticed. Elated by their success, they studied the location carefully so they could return to it at the appointed time, and then set out to find lodging for the remainder of the night.

Their account is rather confused. Presumably, as they went past a dark alley, they were set on by robbers, who were common in that part of town. About four men attacked them, and Harbold suffered a knife wound in the upper left biceps. Maury drew his revolver and disposed of one bandit. The noise attracted the attention of an official patrol, which arrived on the scene and began to club all present into submission. Naturally, Maury did not fire on them, but all he gained by his forbearance was a mild concussion. Being terrorized, McIntyre fled and managed to elude pursuit.

Confined in separate cells, though with numerous fellow prisoners, Maury and Harbold spent a miserable time, much annoyed by vermin. It was two days before the former was brought before a magistrate. In the meantime Harbold apparently contracted a variety of plague from louse bites; furthermore, his wound was badly infected. His immunizations appear to have been ineffective, which suggests that there has been a radical mutational change in a number of viruses during the past two millennia and further suggests the necessity of extensive bacteriological studies before any such expeditions are again undertaken.

Maury had been stripped of all his gear by the police, and was not allowed to have it back to prove his claims of great powers. He was, in fact, considered to be suffering from delusions—insofar as anyone understood his version of Latin— and was in all events an unregistered alien, presumed to be of some Germanic tribe. Though this was before the battle of Teutoburger Wald, there was considerable tension and Germans were suspect. The upshot was that Maury was enslaved and sold to the master of a galley in the Egyptian trade. He spent the rest of his seven-month stay in the past pulling an oar under most unsanitary conditions.

However, the case had aroused the interest of the quaestor, who had Harbold brought to him. Though semi-delirious from fever, Harbold asked for his medical kit, and after the usual linguistic difficulty this was given to him. Under improved conditions of detention, and with the help of penicillin injections, he recovered very slowly. Much impressed, the quaestor finally asked him to demonstrate the other twentieth-century equipment captured from the expedition, and this he did. Naturally, he expected to be treated as an important figure, and the psychic shock must have been considerable when he was accused of witchcraft and all the apparatus was destroyed. It seems that magic was illegal under Roman law; and being a people utterly devoid of scientific curiosity and positively hostile to technological innovation—which could upset their slave-labor economy— they had no further interest in him. Harbold was condemned to be thrown to the lions as soon as he got well enough to provide good sport. The temporal sweep-field was developed just in time to save him.

Meanwhile McIntyre, fleeing, survived the night but the next day had his money stolen by some cut-purse. He tried to sell his gear, but no one was interested enough to give him more than scrap metal prices, and he learned later that he had been cheated even on that transaction. In a few days, McIntyre found himself a penniless foreigner, unable to get work since he lacked the manual skills of the era and certainly unable to convince anyone of the facts. Wisely, he did not even attempt to do this, but eked out a precarious existence as a beggar. He was near starvation when rescued.

The full account may, of course, be found elsewhere. Turning to the medical and psychiatric examinations . . .

FEDERAL BUREAU OF INVESTIGATION

Department of Justice

Washington, D. C.

May 21,1968

Dr. James M. Johnson Office of the President Empire State University New York 30, N. Y.

Dear Sir:

I am in receipt of your communication of the 15th inst. regarding the case of the three missing Romans. Rest assured, this bureau will not give up the case. This bureau never gives up a case. You will be notified when the subjects have been found and arrested.

Yours truly,

K. Edward Windhover

Headquarters of the National Committee of

THE ALL-AMERICAN PARTY

Roosenhower Building

Chicago 19, Illinois

August 9,1993

Mr. Julio Arminelli

Angiosaxon Arms Hotel

New York 8,N.Y.

Dear Julius,

This is going to be kind of a hard note to write, considering how long we have been friends and all, and believe me I still think of you as my old pal and as soon as I can I will see you again and I won’t forget your wife and kids neither. But for the time being we had better stop seeing each other. People are starting to talk, and I can’t afford that. You know how it is.

Me Hercule, it seems like a long time ago we came to the good old USA. And it is, you know, 26 years about. By now we would probably have been down in Pluto’s boarding house from some or other filthy disease if that time machine had not yanked us up to now. These doctors they got nowadays are Georgios verus, huh, old pal?

Remember how scared we was at first? Even after we had busted out, we was scared, all the cars and stuff. I remember Quintilia was about ready to break and run for it, till I told her these things did not hurt other people so why should they hurt us? Only it was you figured out the traffic light system, you always was a sharp boy, Julius. Otherwise we would likely have been arrested then and there. I guess it was us all together who found a low class part of town. We have got a nose for that.

Plain luck, I admit, that there was this big Italian section where we could make ourselves understood and get us a flophouse where they do not ask questions. Not that we have ever been in much danger, even since we got famous. The only people who got a close took at us before we busted out was these science boys at the U and they are schnooks who could not identify their own grandmother in a lineup.

Remember how Quintilia got to work? Some doll, and her job don’t change none in two thousand years! I am glad, though, you made me stop after I mugged that one guy in Central Park. It was a two-hundred buck haul, but you are right, crime don’t pay.

And then that fortune-telling racket you started. Did that ever pull them in! After we had bailed you out the first time and got wise to the law and called it an Orphic religion, we had them, boy, we had them. These religions nowadays don’t know a damn thing about showmanship. But don’t forget, I was the one who cleaned out that big crap game and got us our capital. I am still good at it. When you learned to throw them scientific on the deck of a lousy little galley in a mistral wind, you never forget how, even if the shape is different nowadays.

I don’t think you was right in your last letter, where you said it was luck Quintilia roped that Park Avenue swell and got him to set her up in a swank apartment and all. That doll knows her stuff, I tell you. If we had stayed in Rome, she might have ended up with Caesar. Better this way, though, Wives don’t poison mistresses any more. Not very often. Of course, it was nice having connections through her boy friend so we could get forged papers. This century is almost as bad as Rome where it comes to wanting official papers in triplicate. Imagine me, old Popeye Publius the sailor, with a birth certificate in Boston!

How do you like my English, by the way? I am trying it on you this time, I never did learn to write English so well, though you know I got a Brooklyn accent nobody could tell was put on. I remember the Italians where we hid out at first was surprised how fast we all learned the lingo. But hell, when they spoke a hundred languages in the Roman Empire, you had to be good at them or go under, isn’t that so? You write just like a college professor, take it from me.

In fact, our busting loose was only the second-best thing that ever happened to us. The best was being born in the Roman slums, or the Ostia waterfront in my case. Sounds funny? Welt, just think of it as the good old School of Hard Knocks. We learned how to handle people back then, because if we did not know how we would end up heaving an oar or feeding the lions, which we did not want to do, and people do not change much. Not big-city working stiffs, anyway.

But I am writing too much about the old days. It is just to show that I still think a lot of you and I am not forgetting you even if we can’t meet again for a while. You see, I am on the National Committee now and I can damn near handpick the next candidates for governor of you-know-what three states—and elect them, by Jupiter’s right eye! Only till our boys are in the saddle, with me behind them pulling all the strings, it just would not do for Big John Brutto, the People’s Pal, to be so close to Julio Arminelli who everybody knows owns all the rackets in New York even if they can’t pin it on him. Once the elections is over, I will look you up for sure, because there is plenty you can do for us and I do not think you will mind getting on the gravy train.

Well, so now I got to close. I had a letter from Quintilia the other day. She has built a new house in Beverly Hills and having ditched Husband Number Six, or is it Seven, she is going to make another movie. Maybe she is over forty years of age now, but mammis Veneris, that gal can still pull them in!

Your Old Friend,

Publius (Big John)